Richard Wormser Papers 1932-1977 (bulk 1934-1973)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Manuscripts, 1934-1975; Series 1
  - Titled manuscripts of fictional works, 1934-1975; Subseries 1
    - Shadow of a Man, Script, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Shadowed, Short story, Manhunt Magazine, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - She May Pass Me By, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - She Was No Fat Lady, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - The Sheriff Takes a Walk, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - The She-Stock Drive, (1 of 2) Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - The She-Stock Drive (2 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - The She-Stock Drive, unpublished, Rough Draft, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - The Ship of Old Men, Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Shirt Tail Rancher, Script, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Showdown Creek, Screenplay, Shooting script, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - The Silent Arrow, Treatment, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Silver Dollar, TV Script, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - The Singing Cats of Siam, Short story, Argosy Magazine, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Six Superior Skirts, TV Script, final draft and working drafts, "77 Sunset Strip", 1959 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Slattery's Range, Novel, Typewritten MS, Originally written as "The Breaks of the Humboldt", 1955 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Smart Sucker, Short story, Manhunt Magazine, Correspondence in folder, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - So Hard to Find, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Sodom and Gomorrah (1 of 2), Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Sodom and Gomorrah (2 of 2), Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sonny Boy, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - South for a Killer, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Spider on the Trail, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Spirit of '76, The, Short Story, Typewritten MS, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - A Square Gets Around, Novel, Typewritten MS, Partial draft with correspondence, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - A Square Gets Around, (fragment), Novel, Typewritten MS, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - State Monument, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - The Stones Cry Out, Novel, Typewritten MS, Filmed as "Let Them Live", 1937 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Story in the Stars, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Sunup, Treatment, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Sure Shot, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Surtee, TV script, Shooting script, "The High Chaparral" TV show, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Suspicion 480, Short story, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - The Sweet Horns of Mexico, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - The Tattooed Sheep, Short Story, Argosy Magazine, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Ten Dollars, Short story, Liberty Magazine, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Ten Little Indians, TV script, Shooting script, "The High Chaparral" TV show, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Tequila, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - The Texas Ranger Story, Screenplay, Shooting script, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - There's an Art in It, Short story, Typewritten MS, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - The Thief of Bagdad, Screenplay, Shooting script, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Thunder, Treatment and script, Typewritten MS, "Thunder" TV show episode "Summer Pasture", undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Time to Do Business, Novel, Typewritten MS, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - To Make a Ploughshare, Short story, Typewritten MS, Two versions in this folder, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Tornado Frances, TV script, Shooting script, "The High Chaparral" TV show, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Turntable, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Twisted, Short story, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Two Pairs to Beat, Short story, Liberty Magazine, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Two Strangers Meet, Short story, Lariat Story magazine, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Under the Crooked Cross, Short story, Bluebook Magazine, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Undercover, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - The Valley of Magic Men, Short story, Typewritten MS, Argosy Magazine, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Vigilante Hideout, Short story, Comic Book, circa 1950 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - The Voodoo Eagle, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Walk Your Own Path, Novel, Typewritten MS, "Navajo Boy's Book", 1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Walk Your Own Road (Unpublished), Novel, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Wasteland, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - The Web, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Where Time Means Nothing, Short story, Typewritten MS, Two versions in this folder, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Wild, Wild West, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, incomplete screenplay, folder includes a "77 Sunset Strip" script fragment, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Window in the Night, A, Short story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Wrap Up the Town (Screenplay), Short Story, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Wrap Up the Town (1 of 2), Novel, Completed MS, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Wrap Up the Town (2 of 2), Novel, Completed MS, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Wyoming, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, Also contains character sketch in folder, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - You Have to Learn Sometime, Long Novellette, Argosy Magazine, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - You're in the Circus Now, Serialized Story, Argosy Magazine, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Untitled manuscripts, Undated; Subseries 2
    - No Title, Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - No Title (337 p., incomplete) (1 of 2), book length MS, Typewritten MS, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - No Title (337 p., incomplete) (2 of 2), book length MS, Typewritten MS, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Title Unknown A, Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Title Unknown B, Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Title Unknown (1 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Title Unknown (2 of 2), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Title Unknown (possibly Southwest: the Restless Sleeper), Novel, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Untitled (Border Book), nonfiction, Typewritten MS, This is a draft of a Southwest history book, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Boys' Book (Untitled), Juvenile Novel, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - MS Fragments, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, Short story, Typewritten MS, Contains "Cooking with a Yunnan Steamer" and two other stories, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Two Untitled Copies (1 Incomplete), Typewritten MS, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - TV Misc., TV scripts, Typewritten MS, Scripts from "Rawhide" and "Death Valley Days", undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Nonfiction manuscripts, 1955-1975; Subseries 3
    - Almanac Confederates, Photocopied material, research material on Confederate fugitives for the People's Almanac, circa 1975 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Canyons for McGraw Hill, Encyclopedia articles, Typewritten MS, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Handbook of Horses, Encyclopedia articles, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - How to Enjoy an Art Museum or Gallery, Essay, Typewritten MS, Correspondence in folder, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Mormon Colonies in Mexico, Encyclopedia articles, Typewritten MS, research material on Mormon settlers for the People's Almanac. Some bio info on Junius Romney, circa 1975 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - New Mexico, Article, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Outlines (states), Encyclopedia articles, Typewritten MS, Outlines for encyclopedia articles about California and New Mexico, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Southwest: The Restless Sleeper (1 of 3), Monograph, Typewritten MS, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Southwest: The Restless Sleeper (2 of 3), Monograph, Typewritten MS, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Southwest: The Restless Sleeper (3 of 3), Monograph, Typewritten MS, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Trip to the Magic Rugs, Article, Typewritten MS, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Tubac, non-fiction book, Typewritten MS, Historical survey of Tubac, AZ, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Very West, Somewhat South, Monograph, Typewritten MS, An abbreviated version of Southwest: The Restless Sleeper, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - World on Your Table, The, Monograph, Typewritten MS, Treatise on aquariums, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts on Cooking, 1955-1969; Subseries 4
    - Cooking With a Silver Spoon, Cook book, Typewritten MS, "by Rosalea,", 1955 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - How to Cook a Running Dinner, Culinary article, Typewritten MS, Sold to Ford Times, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Southwest Cookery, Cook book, Typewritten MS, Other drafts in folder, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Southwest Cookery, or At Home on the Range, Cook book, Typewritten MS, possibly gallery drafts, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Use Pluck in the Kitchen, Cooking article, Typewritten MS, submission to Gourmet Magazine, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - You Gotta Have Gout, Cooking article, Typewritten MS, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Personal and Business Materials, 1951-1977; Series 2
  These are the personal and business papers of Richard Wormser. They comprise his autobiographical material and his business correspondence.
  - Autobiographical material, 1957-1967; Subseries 1
    This subseries is a group of autobiographies Wormser wrote at different points in his career as well as a few attempts at longer forms of autobiography. Among the latter are "How to become a Complete Nonentity" and "Worlds" which give a vivid portrait of life in the Jewish community of the Upper West Side in the early 20th Century and a colorful portrayal of the magazine trade during the Great Depression.
    - Autobiography, Typewritten MS, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Biography, Autobiography, Typewritten MS, circa 1967 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - How to Become a Complete Nonentity, Autobiography, Typewritten MS, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - One of My Lost Worlds, Autobiography, Typewritten MS, material about his childhood in NYC. An additional story is grouped into this folder, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Worlds, Autobiography, Typewritten MS, three drafts of part of an autobiography, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1977; Subseries 2
    While most of the correspondence relating to individual manuscripts was grouped along with the manuscripts in question, Mr. Wormser himself separated out the larger collections of business and fan letters into their own folders. They are labeled by the name of the story they to which they pertain.
    - Correspondence/Contracts, 1954-1977 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Border Book Correspondence, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Cavalcade- Indians, Correspondence, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - The Lonesome Quarter, Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Mapleson's Memoirs, Correspondence, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Mapleson's Memoirs, Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - No Bad Peace Correspondence, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Ride a Northbound Horse Correspondence, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Oversized Materials, 1936-1955; Series III
  These are stories published in larger format magazines and manuscripts written on legal-sized paper.
  - The Blackbird, Short story, Saturday Evening Post, 1942 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Come Home Not Marching, Short story, Collier's, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - The Courtship of Baptiste Brown, Short Story, Saturday Evening Post, 1941 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Golden Tide, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1952 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - High Iron, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Let the Young Men Smoke, Short Story, Saturday Evening Post, 1943 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Red Horizon, Screenplay, Typewritten MS, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - The Road to Carmichael's, Novel, Saturday Evening Post, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Sleep All Winter, Screenplay (1 of 2), 1949 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Sleep All Winter (2 of 2), Novel, Esquire Magazine, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - With Dignity, Short Story, Collier's, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 6)